Guide to George Washington University Catalogs, etc. Cubb.00160
Cubberley Education Library
George Washington University
1855-1976
Cubberley Education Library
Cubb.00160
240 item(s)
Located in Washington, D.C. Founded in 1821 as Columbian College. Became Columbian University in 1873. Changed name to George Washington University in 1904. Opened Virginia campus in 1991.
District of Columbia
- Columbian College, 1855-1861; 3 item(s) Catalogs for 1855/56-1856/57, 1860/61 bound with catalogs for Columbian University.
- Columbian University, 1872-1904; 39 item(s) Catalogs for 1872/73-1877/78, 1882/83, 1884/85, 1891/92 bound with catalogs for Columbian College; Bound together 1892/93-1896/97 & bound together 1897/98-1900/01 Separate catalogs for 1901/02-1904
  - Columbian University Law School, 1898-1901; 2 item(s) Catalogs for 1898/99 & 1900/01
    Law schools
  - Columbian University Medical School, 1886-1902; 10 item(s)
    Medical colleges
    - Columbian University Medical Department, 1886-1887; 4 item(s) Catalogs for 1886/87
    - Columbian University National Medical College, Medical Department, 1890-1893; 2 item(s) Catalogs for 1890/91 & 1892/93
    - Columbian University Medical Department, 1895-1898; 3 item(s) Announcement and catalogs for 1895/96-1897/98
    - Columbian University Medical School, 1901-1902; 1 item(s) Catalog for 1901/02
- George Washington University, 1905-1978; 198 item(s) Catalogs for 1905-1930/31, 1932/33-1941/42, 1944/45-1948/49, 1950/51-1953/54, 1955/56-1969/70, 1971/72-1972/73, 1975/76, 1977/78
  - George Washington University Alumni Number/Directory, 1905-1938; 5 item(s) Bulletins for 1905-1908, 1938
  - George Washington University Report of the President, 1912-1916; 2 item(s) Reports for 1912/13 & 1915/16
  - George Washington University Law School, 1914-1969; 45 item(s) Announcements for 1914/15-1917/18, 1919/20-1931/32, 1933/34-1935/36, 1937/38-1946/47 Catalogs for 1947/48, 1949/50, 1952/53-1956/57, 1958/59-1959/60
    - George Washington University Department of Law, 1911-1914; 3 item(s) Announcements for 1911/12-1913/14
    - George Washington University Law School Summer Term, 1953; 1 item(s) Bulletin for 1953
    - George Washington University National Law Center, 1963-1969; 3 item(s) Bulletins for 1963/64, 1965/66, 1968/69
  - George Washington University School of Medicine and Health Sciences, 1905-1978; 29 item(s) Catalog for 1977-1978
    - George Washington University Faculty of Medicine, 1905; 1 item(s) Catalog for 1905
    - George Washington University Department of Medicine, 1906-1911; 3 item(s) Catalogs for 1906-1907, 1911
    - George Washington University Medical School, 1921-1928; 7 item(s) Announcements for 1921/22-1927/28
    - George Washington University School of Medicine, 1928-1970; 25 item(s) Bulletins for 1928-1933, 1935-1938, 1942/43-1943/44, 1945/46, 1950/51-1951/52, 1953/54-1955/56, 1957-1958, 1960, 1962-1963, 1968/69-1969/70
  - George Washington University School of Engineering and Applied Science, 1965-1977; 6 item(s) Bulletins for 1965/66-1966/67, 1971/72-1972/73, 1975/76
    Engineering -- Programs
    - George Washington University Graduate Study and Research in Energy, Resources and Environment, 1976-1977; 1 item(s) Program description and courses for 1976/77
  - George Washington University Department of Arts and Sciences, 1926-1927; 1 item(s) Announcements for 1926/27
  - George Washington University Report of the Comptroller, 1951-1952; 2 item(s) Reports for 1951 & 1952
  - George Washington University Report of the Treasurer, 1953-1955; 3 item(s) Reports for 1953-1955
  - The George Washington University in the Nation's Capital Bulletin Pictorial Issue, November 1955; 1 item(s)
  - George Washington University Summer Sessions, 1961; 1 item(s) Bulletin for 1961
  - George Washington University Institute for Educational Leadership Washington Internships in Education, 1973-1974; 1 item(s) Internships for 1973/74
- Benjamin Franklin University, 1935-1976; 30 item(s) Yearbooks for 1935-1936, 1938, 1940-1957/58, 1959/60, 1967/68-1973/74, 1975/76; Formerly Pace Institute (founded in 1907 by Homer S. Pace). Established by John Thomas Kennedy in 1925. In 1987 merged into the School of Business and Public Management of George Washington University.
  Business schools